# ARIWAODO-ABACHE ALOAYE FAITH

Contact Details: 18 AFOLABI STREET, OKOTA, LAGOS STATE

Phone: +2348133499023, +2348057418878

E-mail: fayeabache@gmail.com/faye\_ariwaodo@icloud.com

#### **PERSONAL DATA**

L.G.A: Etsako East State of Origin: EDO

Nationality: Nigerian Sex: Female

# **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I am a Python Full stack developer who has worked solo and with teams in building projects.

I have experience working in an oil and gas firm as a system analyst with strong technical skills.

with my love for software and development, I switched from being a system analyst to being a software developer.

Faith is vast in in React, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, Django, MySQL amongst others.

Soft Skills: Remote, Onsite, Problem-solving, Mentoring, communication skills.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

# TECHSTUDIO ACADEMY, LAGOS STATE.

# **Python Full Stack Software Developer** (January 2022 to date) <u>General Specifications</u>

### Frontend:

- Ensure user experience determines design choices.
- Developing features to enhance the user experience.
- Striking a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensuring web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Building reusable code for future use.
- Optimizing web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Utilizing a variety of markup languages to write web pages.
- Maintaining brand consistency throughout the design.

### **Backend:**

- Develop soft-ware against given designs or specification using the Django framework
- Analyse and fix Bugs reported within the existing code base.

## **OPITMUM PETROLEUM DEVELOPMENT, LAGOS STATE**

**Computer Analyst/Administrator** (October 2016 – November 2021) **General Job specifications** 

- · Research and evaluate new technologies, consult with clients
- Identify the organizational needs on IT systems, making suggestions on New IT innovations and new functionality to systems.
- Oversee installations and test systems making sure every of the system is updated and working normally.

- Manage, maintain, and repair IT systems including diagnosing and repairing faults, resolving network issues and
  installing and configuring hardware and software.
- Preparing, organizing, and storing information in paper/digital form

### **Administrator**

# **General Job specifications**

- Answering incoming calls; taking messages and re-directing calls as required.
- Taking Minutes
- Diary Management and arranging appointments, booking meeting rooms and conference facilities
- Organising travel and accommodation for board of Directors/Executives
- General office management such as ordering stationery
- Managing the Company's website and social media accounts.
- Dealing with queries via emails and phone.
- Managing and scheduling meetings and travel/ accommodation itinerary for Management Staff

### **GISTME COMMUNICATIONS, LAGOS STATE**

# IT Personnel/ Content Developer (November 2015- September 2016)

### **General Job specifications**

- Install and configure software and computer systems
- Troubleshooting and resolving issues with software or hardware
- Walk colleagues or clients through steps to help them resolve their technical problems
- Support the implementation of new solutions or applications
- Researching organization related topics, preparing well structured drafts using digital word processing and publishing platforms
- Creating and distributing marketing contents to advertise the company and its products

### COLLEGE OF IMMACULATE CONCEPTION(National Youth Service Corp (N.Y.S.C), ENUGU STATE

### Computer Instructor (August 2014 – July 2015)

#### **General Job specifications**

- Planning lessons and activities that facilitate students acquisition of basic and advanced computer skill, instructing
  in a manner that develops students confidence on the abilities
- Observing and managing classroom dynamics

#### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# **XATH RESOURCES LTD, LAGOS STATE**

**Volunteer/Administrative Officer** (August 2013 – March 2014)

- Preparing, organizing and storing information in paper/digital form
- Dealing with queries via emails and phone. Managing and scheduling meetings and travel/ accommodation itinery for Management Staff

#### **EDUCATION**

- NIGERIAN INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT CHARTERED (MEMBER) (2015)
- METHODIST UNIVERSITY, GHANA (NOVEMBER, 2013)

**Bachelor of Information Technology** 

## • TUNYO COMPREHENSIVE COLLEGE, LAGOS STATE (2009)

West African Senior School Certificate Examination

## **SKILLS**

### **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Package: MS-Office 2010, XP (Word, Excel, Power Point), Web development and graphic designs

Internet: E-mail, Surfing and Research

## **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Excellent in English intermediate level of Yoruba

## **OTHER SKILLS**

- Administrative, Research, Litigation and drafting skills
- Good interpersonal and communication skills
- Self-motivated, goal-oriented and a good team player
- Good planning, scheduling, organizational and managerial skill
- Ability to multitask, prioritize and resilience in getting assigned-tasks done
- Good time management skill and ability to work with little or no supervision

**HOBBIES**: Learning new things, organizing and planning, networking, travelling, making new friends, solving problems. **REFERENCES**: available upon request.